Guide to the Research Institute for the Study of Man (RISM) Vertical Files RISM.VF.1
New York University Archives
- Caribbean Area
  - Caribbean Area: Literature, Bibliography (Box 6)
    - West Indian Literature; A Select Bibliography compiled by the University of the West Indies Library, 1964; RISM 17480; University of the West Indies (Mona, Jamaica). Library; 32 pages (Box 6)
  - Caribbean Area: Literature, History and Criticism (Box 6)
    - The Contribution of the West Indians to Literature; Lecture, Guyana Public Library, 1958; RISM 17474; Seymour, A. J. (Arthur J.); 6 pages (Box 6)
      Caribbean literature.; History and criticism.
    - Making West Indian Literature, undated; RISM 27380; Morris, Mervyn; 23 pages; 23.0 (Box 6)
    - The Literary Situation in the Contemporary Caribbean, 1956 (Box 6)
      History and criticism.; Caribbean literature.
  - Caribbean Area: Magic (Box 6)
    - Obeah: Magic and Social Structure in the Lesser Antilles, 1948; RISM 20273; Sereno, Renzo; p. 15-31. (Box 6)
      Magic.; Caribbean Area.
    - The West Indian Supernatural World: Belief Integration in a Pluralistic Society, 1975; RISM 23928; Beck, Jane C., 1941-; p. 235-244. (Box 6)
    - On the Early Use and Origin of the Term 'Obeah' in Barbados and the Anglophone Caribbean, 2001; RISM 26660; Handler, Jerome S.; p. 87-100. (Box 6)
    - Obeah: Healing and Protection in West Indian Slave Life, 2004; Bilby, Kenneth M., 1953-; Handler, Jerome S. (Box 6)
  - Caribbean Area: Management (Box 6)
    - The Caribbean Businessman, 1979; RISM 20274; Da Silva, Frank; p. 31-34. (Box 6)
      Management.; Caribbean Area.
  - Caribbean Area: Management, Study and Teaching (Box 6)
    - Management Studies in the Commonwealth Caribbean, 1974; RISM 20275; 36 pages (Box 6)
      Management.; Caribbean Area.; Study and teaching.
    - The Role of Management Studies in the Faculty of Social Sciences, 1983; RISM 20276; Williams, Randolph F.; 6 pages (Box 6)
      Management.; Study and teaching.; Caribbean Area.
  - Caribbean Area: Marine Resources (Box 6)
    - Message from The President of the United States Transmitting the Convention for the Protection and Development of the Marine Environment of the Wider Caribbean Region, 1984; RISM 20277; United States. President (1981-1989: Reagan); 43 pages (Box 6)
      Caribbean Area.; Marine resources.
    - Developing a Cooperative International Program in Marine Policy, 1982; RISM 20278; Silva, Maynard Edward, 1949-; 20 pages (Box 6)
    - Undersea Caribbean, 1974; RISM 20279; Grotell, Al; p. 10-15. (Box 6)
  - Caribbean Area: Maritime Law (Box 6)
    - The Caribbean Basin and Recent Developments in the Law of the Sea; Human Rights in the Commonwealth Caribbean: An International Relations Perspective, 1983; RISM 20280; Francis, Anselm; 27 pages (Box 6)
      Caribbean Area.; Maritime law.
    - The Caribbean Basin and the Law of the Sea, 1982; RISM 20281; Francis, Anselm; 27 pages (Box 6)
  - Caribbean Area: Marriage (Box 6)
    - A Typology of Caribbean Mating Systems, 1963; RISM 20282; Otterbein, Keith F.; 6 pages (Box 6)
      Caribbean Area.; Marriage
    - Mating is Marriage in the Caribbean, 1972; RISM 20283; Berleant-Schiller, Riva; p. 66-79. (Box 6)
    - A Gross Mating Table for a West Indian Population, 1961; RISM 20284; Roberts, G. W. (George W.); p. 198-217. (Box 6)
      Marriage; Caribbean Area.
  - Caribbean Area: Mass Media (Box 6)
    - A Free Press in a Free Society, 1985; RISM 20286; Bustamante Institute of Public and International Affairs; 38 pages (Box 6)
      Mass media.; Caribbean Area.
    - Catalogue of Recorded Programmes, 1957; RISM 20287; University College of the West Indies (Mona, Jamaica). Department of Extra-Mural Studies. Radio Education Unit; unpaged. (Box 6)
    - The U.S. and the Caribbean: Partners in Communication, 1984; RISM 20288; Dougan, Diana, Lady; 4 pages (Box 6)
    - Ricky Singh and the Caribbean Media; Address at the Caribbean Conference of Intellectual Workers (I and II), 1982-1984; RISM 20289; Singh, Rickey; 28 pages (Box 6)
    - The PRG Collapse: Implications for a Free Press and the New World Information Order in the Caribbean, 1984; RISM 20290; Deosaran, Ramesh; 14 pages (Box 6)
  - Caribbean Area: Medical Research (Box 6)
    - Department Social and Preventive Medicine Unit of the University of the West Indies, 1965; RISM 20291; University of the West Indies (Mona, Jamaica). Department of Social and Preventive Medicine; various paging. (Box 6)
      Research (document genres).; Medicine.; Caribbean Area.
    - Address by Prime Minister, Dr. Eric Williams, Opening of the 21st Scientific Meeting of the Commonwealth Medical Research Council, 1976; RISM 20292; Trinidad and Tobago. Office of the Prime Minister; 4 pages (Box 6)
      Medicine.; Research (document genres).; Caribbean Area.
  - Caribbean Area: Medical Research, Bibliography (Box 6)
    - Health Problems in the Caribbean: An Annotated Bibliography from the West Indian Collection at the Medical Library, University of the West Indies, 1987; RISM 20293; Mansingh, Laxmi; 24 pages (Box 6)
      Bibliography.; Caribbean Area.; Medicine.; Research (document genres).
  - Caribbean Area: Mental Health (Box 6)
    - Mental Health and Industrial Relations: Some Reflections on the West Indian Historical Experience, 1974; RISM 20294; Trinidad and Tobago. Office of the Prime Minister; 5 pages (Box 6)
      Caribbean Area.; Mental health.
    - Caribbean Folk Beliefs and Western Psychiatry, 1985; RISM 20295; Schwartz, Dorthy; p. 26-30. (Box 6)
    - Psychotherapy and Cultural Adapation in the Caribbean, 1981; RISM 20296; Lefley, Harriet P.; p. 3-16. (Box 6)
  - Caribbean Area: Mental Illness (Box 6)
    - The View from Monkey Mountain, 1975; RISM 20299; Beaubrun, Michael H.; p. 257-266. (Box 6)
      Caribbean Area.; Mental illness.
    - Planning and Utilization of Mental Health Resources within the Caribbean, 1969; RISM 23183; Beaubrun, Michael H.; 12 pages (Box 6)
    - Report on the Census of Caribbean Mental Hospitals, 1960; RISM 24961; Rubin, Vera D.; 6 pages (Box 6)
  - Caribbean Area: Mental Retardation (Box 6)
    - Caribbean Association on Mental Retardation and Other Developmental Disabilities: 20 Year Review, 1970-1990, RISM 20302; Caribbean Association on Mental Retardation and other Developmental Disability; 32 pages (Box 6)
      Caribbean Area.; Mental retardation.
  - Caribbean Area: Methodist Church (Box 6)
    - West Indies Methodist Bicentenary, 1760-1960: Gilbert Estate and Memorial Church, undated; RISM 20303; Methodist Church (Great Britain). West Indies; 4 pages (Box 6)
      Caribbean Area.; Methodist church.
    - The Conference of the Methodist Church in the Caribbean and Americas; Summary of the Proceedings, 1967; RISM 20304; 4 pages (Box 6)
    - Methodism in the Caribbean with Particular Reference to Autonomy; William Fish Lecture, 1966; RISM 20305; Sherlock, Hugh; 6 pages (Box 6)
    - Conference of the Methodist Church in the Caribbean and the Americas, undated; RISM 21608; Sherlock, Hugh; 6 pages (Box 6)
  - Caribbean Area: Migration, Internal (Box 6)
    - Report of the Conference on Movement of Persons within a British Caribbean Federation, 1955; RISM 16216; 7 pages (Box 6)
      Caribbean Area.; Migration, Internal
    - Education and Rural Urban Migration in Latin America and the Caribbean, undated; RISM 20307; MacDonald, Leatrice D.; p. 31-37. (Box 6)
    - Buttressing the Sugar Revolution: West Indian and European Labor Migration to Puerto Rico, 1800-1850, 1984; RISM 25021; Scarano, Francisco A. (Francisco Antonio); 30 pages (Box 6)
      Migration, Internal; Caribbean Area.
    - Problems of Collecting Population Statistics; A Video Transcription, 1976; RISM 25815; Bourne, Luther; p. 5 (Box 6)
    - Decision-Making and Statistics, 1976; RISM 25817; Harewood, Jack; p. 7 (Box 6)
  - Caribbean Area: Military Bases, American (Box 6)
    - Agreement Between the Government of the Federation of the West Indies and the Government of the United States of America concerning United States Defence Areas in the Federation of the West Indies, 1961; RISM 20308; Great Britain. Colonial Office; 37 pages (Box 6)
      Military bases, American; Caribbean Area.
  - Caribbean Area: Mineral Industries (Box 6)
    - The Mineral Industry of the Islands of the Caribbean (Bahamas, Barbados, Bermuda, Cuba, Dominican Republic, Haiti, Jamaica, Martinique, Netherlands Antilles, Trinidad and Tobago), 1965-1984; RISM 20309; United States. Bureau of Mines; 5 items; 1965, 1975, 1976, 1983, 1984; Library has: 1965, 1975-1976, and 1983-1984. (Box 6)
      Mineral industries.; Caribbean Area.
  - Caribbean Area: Mines and Mineral Resources (Box 6)
    - Mineral Resources of the Greater Antilles, 1941; RISM 20314; Meyerhoff, Howard A. (Howard Augustus), 1899-; p. 265-270. (Box 6)
      Mines and mineral resources.; Caribbean Area.
    - The Ring of Metals: Sociopolitical Impact of Caribbean Basin Mineral Resource Exploitation, 1984; RISM 20315; Maloney, Thomas J.; 24 pages (Box 6)
  - Caribbean Area: Money (Box 6)
    - Monetary Integration in CARICOM, 1991; RISM 20316; Bennett, Karl M.; 12 pages (Box 6)
      Money.; Caribbean Area.
    - Economics of Devaluation Under West Indian Conditions, 1972; RISM 20317; Demas, William G.; 19 pages (Box 6)
      Caribbean Area.; Money.
    - A Common Currency for the Caribbean, 1992; RISM 20318; Worrell, DeLisle; 32 pages (Box 6)
  - Caribbean Area: Music (Box 6)
    - Reggae, Calypso, Soca: Now It's 'Cadence' from the 'Little Islands', 1978; RISM 20319; Lee, Robert; 3 pages (Box 6)
      Caribbean Area.; Music.
    - The Cross-Cultural Dimension of Afro-Inspired Music, undated; RISM 23209; Preiswerk, Roy, 1934-1982; p. 7-10. (Box 6)
    - La Structuration Ethnolinguistique de la Chanson Caribeenne Anglophone, 1984; RISM 24935; Aly, Jacques; p. 55-67. (Box 6)
  - Caribbean Area: Moral Development (Box 6)
    - The Development of Moral Reasoning in Belize, Trinidad-Tobago, and the U.S.A., 1986; RISM 22993; Gielen, Uwe P. (Uwe Peter), 1940-; p. 178-207. (Box 6)
      Caribbean Area.; Moral development.
  - Caribbean Area: Mythology (Box 6)
    - History, Fable and Myth in the Caribbean & Guianas; Text of the 1970 Edgar Mittelholzer Memorial Lecture, RISM 20320; Harris, Wilson; 32 pages (Box 6)
      Caribbean Area.; Mythology.
  - Caribbean Area: Names, Geographical (Box 6)
    - The Heraldry of the Commonwealth Caribbean: Banner Exhibition to Commemorate the 350th Anniversary of Parliament, 1639-1989, RISM 20321; Rudder, Ann; 23 pages (Box 6)
      Caribbean Area.; Names, Geographical.
    - Lucayan Toponyms, 1991; RISM 23319; Granberry, Julian; 12 pages; p. 3-12. (Box 6)
      Names, Geographical.; Caribbean Area.
  - Caribbean Area: National Parks and Reserves (Box 6)
    - National Parks in the Caribbean Area, 1973; RISM 20322; Towle, Edward L.; 19 pages (Box 6)
      National parks and reserves.; Caribbean Area.
  - Caribbean Area: National Security (Box 6)
    - Memorandum of Understanding Between the Government of Antigua and Barbuda, Barbados, Commonwealth of Dominica, St. Lucia, and St. Vincent and the Grenadines; Relating to Security and Military Co-Operation 1982, Part 1, 1983; RISM 20323; 7 pages (Box 6)
      National security; Caribbean Area.
  - Caribbean Area: Nationalism (Box 6)
    - West Indian Nationalism: A Survey of West Indian Leaders Reveals That Liberalism May Wane As Nationalism Goes Through New Phases, 1964; RISM 20324; Moskos, Charles C.; p. 16-18. (Box 6)
      Nationalism.; Caribbean Area.
    - Caribbean Museums and National Identity, 2004; Cummins, Alissandra (Box 6)
  - Caribbean Area: Natural History (Box 6)
    - A Narrative of the Smithsonian-Bredin Caribbean Expedition, 1956, 1957; RISM 20325; Schmitt, Waldo L. (Waldo Lasalle), 1887-1977; 18 pages; p. 443-460. (Box 6)
      Natural history.; Caribbean Area.
    - Narrative of the 1958 Smithsonian-Bredin Caribbean Expedition, 1959; RISM 20326; Schmitt, Waldo L. (Waldo Lasalle), 1887-1977; 12 pages; p. 419-430. (Box 6)
  - Caribbean Area: Nature in Literature (Box 6)
    - Natural Hedonism: The Invention of Caribbean Islands as Tropical Playgrounds, 2002; RISM 27403; Sheller, Mimi; 20 pages; 20.0 (Box 6)
      Nature in literature.; Caribbean Area.
  - Caribbean Area: Navigation, Primitive (Box 6)
    - Pre-Columbian Seafaring Capabilities in the Lesser Antilles, undated; RISM 22994; Nicholson, Desmond V.; p. 98-105. (Box 6)
      Caribbean Area.; Navigation, Primitive.
  - Caribbean Area: News Agencies (Box 6)
    - The Caribbean News Agency: Third World Model, 1981; RISM 20327; Cuthbert, Marlene; 41 pages (Box 6)
      Caribbean Area.; News agencies.
  - Caribbean Area: Nutrition (Box 6)
    - Caribbean Calorie Counter, 1990; RISM 20328; Thompson, Patricia Y.; 30 pages (Box 6)
      Caribbean Area.; Nutrition
    - Improving Household Food Security in the Commonwealth Caribbean, 1992; RISM 20329; Leslie, Kenneth A.; 8 pages (Box 6)
    - Nutrition and Self-Reliance: A Look at the Caribbean and the Rural South, 1977; RISM 20330; Ingman, Stanley R.; 13 pages (Box 6)
    - Nutrition in the British West Indies, 1946; RISM 20332; Platt, B. S., (Benjamin Stanley), 1903-; 38 pages (Box 6)
  - Caribbean Area: Peasantry (Box 6)
    - Reflections on Caribbean Peasantries, 1983; RISM 20333; Mintz, Sidney W. (Sidney Wilfred), 1922-2015; p. 1-17. (Box 6)
      Caribbean Area.; Peasants.
    - Aboriginal and Peasant Cultures of the Caribbean, 1992; RISM 20334; Kimber, C. T. (Clarissa Thérèse), 1929-; p. 153-163. (Box 6)
    - Fiji and the West Indies, 1946; RISM 20335; Pim, Alan, Sir, 1871-1958; p. 77-114. (Box 6)
      Peasants.; Caribbean Area.
    - Life in a Mirror, No. 8: Peasant and Middle-Class, undated; RISM 20336; University of the West Indies (Mona, Jamaica). University Radio Service; 9 pages (Box 6)
    - Caribbean Social Type: Neither "Peasant" Nor "Proletarian", 1967; RISM 24028; Frucht, Richard, 1936-1979; p. 295-300. (Box 6)
    - Notes on Peasant Development in the West Indies since 1838, undated; RISM 24143; Marshall, Woodville K.; p. 252-263. (Box 6)
    - The Question of Caribbean Peasantries: A Comment, 1961; RISM 24176; Mintz, Sidney W. (Sidney Wilfred), 1922-2015; p. 31-34. (Box 6)
    - The Powerless Producers; A Video Transcription, 1976; RISM 25818; Huggins, George R.; p. 21 (Box 6)
  - Caribbean Area: Periodicals (Box 6)
    - Caribbean Quarterly; Contents of Individual Past Issues; Vol. 2, No. 3-Vol. 11, Nos. 1-2, undated; RISM 24868; University of the West Indies (Mona, Jamaica). Department of Extra-mural Studies; 7 pages (Box 6)
      Periodicals; Caribbean Area.
  - Caribbean Area: Petroleum Industry and Trade (Box 6)
    - Oil in the Caribbean: Focus on Trinidad, 1976; RISM 20337; 32 pages (Box 6)
      Petroleum industry and trade.; Caribbean Area.
    - Comments on Dr. A.A. Meyerhoff's Article" Economic Impact of Petroleum, with Particular Reference to the Caribbean", 1977; RISM 20338; Morales-Cardona, Tomás; 5 pages (Box 6)
      Caribbean Area.; Petroleum industry and trade.
    - Comentarios a la Respuesta del Dr. A. A. Meyerhoff, 1977; RISM 20339; Morales-Cardona, Tomás; 5 pages (Box 6)
    - Economic Impact of Petroleum, with Particular Reference to the Caribbean; Summary of Lecture, 1977; RISM 20340; Meyerhoff, A. A. (Arthur Augustus), 1928-; 7 pages (Box 6)
    - Oil and the Caribbean, 1979; RISM 20341; Thomson, R. A.; 2 pages (Box 6)
  - Caribbean Area: Pineapple (Box 6)
    - Fruit for the Gods, undated; RISM 20342; Jane, Charles W. E.; 3 pages (Box 6)
      Caribbean Area.; Pineapple.
  - Caribbean Area: Plantations (Box 6)
    - The Codrington Papers: The Property of a Gentleman, undated; RISM 20343; p. 65-75 (Box 6)
      Caribbean Area.; Plantations.
    - Plantations as Institutions Under Stress in the Caribbean Today: A Historical-Geographic Approach, 1981; RISM 20344; Innes, Frank C.; p. 81-87. (Box 6)
    - Absentee-Proprietorship in the British West Indies To About 1850, 1964; RISM 24051; Hall, Douglas; p. 15-35. (Box 6)
  - Caribbean Area: Poetry (Box 6)
    - The Morning Star, 1964; RISM 17356; Levy, Wesley; 35 pages (Box 6)
      Caribbean poetry.
    - Let Not The Great, 1960; RISM 17357; Sookhdeo, Jaikissoon; 35 pages (Box 6)
    - The Four and Other Poems, 1953-1954; RISM 20347; Hopkinson, Abdur-Rahman Slade, 1934-; 20 pages (Box 6)
    - Voices; Independence Anniversary, 1964; 20 pages (Box 6)
      Caribbean Area.; Poetry.
    - Eh Bien Oui!: An Anthology of Twenty Poems in English and Creolese, undated; RISM 20348; Fortun‌, José Ramon (Box 6)
    - Thirty Caribbean Limericks, 1984; RISM 18924; 5 pages (Box 6)
  - Caribbean Area: Poetry, Bibliography (Box 6)
    - West Indian Poetry in English, 1900-1970: A Selected Bibliography, 1972; RISM 17469; Asein, S.O. (Samuel O.); p. 12-15. (Box 6)
      Caribbean poetry.; Bibliography.
  - Caribbean Area: Poetry: History and Criticism (Box 6)
    - West Indian Poetry, 1900-1970: A Study on Cultural Decolonisation, ca. 1971; RISM 17358; Baugh, Edward; 20 pages (Box 6)
      History and criticism.; Caribbean poetry.
    - West Indian Poetry: Some Problems of Assessment, 1971; RISM 20349; Rohlehr, Gordon, 1942-; p. 11-14. (Box 6)
      Caribbean poetry.; History and criticism.
    - Higgledy, Piggledy, My Black Hen: Poetry in Secondary Education, 1965; RISM 24595; Gray, Cecil; p. 36-53. (Box 6)
    - Shake Keane's Poetic Legacy, 2000; RISM 27393; Nanton, Philip; 7 pages; 7.0 (Box 6)
  - Caribbean Area: Politicians (Box 6)
    - Black Leaders of the West Indies, 1967; RISM 20200; Thompson, Era Bell; p. 76-89. (Box 6)
      Politicians.; Caribbean Area.
  - Caribbean Area: Politics and Government (Box 6)
    - An Outline of Political Thought: Democracy, Socialism, Imperialism, 1985; RISM 15930; Brown, Orville; 23 pages; 23.0 (Box 6)
      Politics and government.; Caribbean Area.
    - The Assassins, 1980; RISM 17380; Singham, A. W.; 2 pages; p. 37-38. (Box 6)
    - Emergencia del Estado-Nacion y Neocolonizacion en el Caribe, 1981; RISM 17382; Pierre-Charles, Gérard; p. 13-28 (Box 6)
      Caribbean Area.; Politics and government.
    - Metropolitan Influences and the Dependency Problem: Illusion and Reality in Caribbean Politics, 1981; RISM 17383; Green, Edward C.; p. 99-118. (Box 6)
    - La Importancia Estrategica de la Cuenca del Caribe en Terminos Politicos y Economicos, undated; RISM 17384; Manley, Michael, 1924-1997; p. 5-20. (Box 6)
    - Observations for Panel Discussion On: The Caribbean - Crisis and Response, 1984; RISM 17385; Singh, Rickey; 5 pages (Box 6)
    - Prospects in the Caribbean, 1963; RISM 17386; Sherlock, Philip Manderson, Sir; p. 744-756. (Box 6)
    - Radical Winds in the Caribbean, May 1980; RISM 17387; Szulc, Tad; p. 16-19+ (Box 6)
    - Zone des Caraibes, 1953; RISM 17389; Williams, Eric Eustace, 1911-1981; p. 159-172. (Box 6)
    - The Caribbean Revolution: Tasks and Perspectives; Address at the Caribbean Anti-Imperialist Conference, 1972; RISM 17390; Jagan, Cheddi; 21 pages (Box 6)
    - Better The Known Than The Unknown, 1980; RISM 17391; Rickards, Colin; 30 pages; p. 5-7. (Box 6)
    - Short-Range Prospects in the British Caribbean, 1961; RISM 17392; Smith, M. G. (Michael Garfield); 28 pages (Box 6)
    - Levels of West Indian Government, 1961; RISM 17399; Lowenthal, David; 59 pages (Box 6)
    - The Caribbean Strategic Vacuum, 1980; RISM 17400; Sims, Richard; 24 pages (Box 6)
    - The Political Socialization of Marginal Groups, 1967; RISM 17401; Singham, A. W.; p. 182-198. (Box 6)
    - The Caribbean, 1982; RISM 17402; Lowenthal, Abraham F.; p. 112-145. (Box 6)
    - Democracy and Crisis in the Eastern Caribbean: The Cases of Antigua and Grenada, 1986; RISM 17403; Henry, Paget; 28 pages (Box 6)
    - The Caribbean After Grenada, 1984; RISM 18258; Crossette, Barbara; p. 51-53, 58-66. (Box 6)
    - Communique of the Fifth Meeting of Conference of Heads of Government of the Caribbean Community, 1984; RISM 20196; 10 pages (Box 6)
    - Short-Range Prospects in the British Caribbean, 1962; RISM 20031; Smith, M. G. (Michael Garfield); p. 392-408. (Box 6)
    - Tracking a Political Sea Change, 1990; RISM 23173; Braveboy-Wagner, Jacqueline Anne; 2 pages; p. 8-9. (Box 6)
    - To Be or Not to Be: Jamaica, Belize and the Third World, 1981; RISM 23174; Thorndike, Tony; 15 pages (Box 6)
    - Nationhood, Identity, and a Democratic Way of Life! "The Challenges Facing Caribbean Peoples", 1987; RISM 23220; Brizan, George I.; 3 pages (Box 6)
    - The Politics of the Caribbean, 1971; RISM 24123; Lewis, Gordon K.; 32 pages (Box 6)
    - The Commonwealth Caribbean, 1971; RISM 24148; McDonald, Frank; 39 pages (Box 6)
    - The Caribbean and North America, 1971; RISM 24256; Silvert, Kalman H.; 19 pages (Box 6)
    - Problems of National Development in the West Indies, 1965; RISM 24264; Springer, Hugh W.; 20 pages (Box 6)
    - Some Thoughts on the Political Economy of the Caribbean, 1972; RISM 17381; Rodney, Walter Anthony, 1942-1980; 14 pages (Box 6)
    - CASHA; Journal of the Caribbean Liberation Movement, Vol. 1, No. 1, 1973; 7 pages (Box 6)
  - Caribbean Area: Population (Box 6)
    - Prospects for Population Growth in the West Indies, 1961; RISM 17418; Roberts, G. W. (George W.); 15 pages (Box 6)
      Caribbean Area.; Population.
    - The Caribbean Islands, 1958; RISM 17419; Roberts, G. W. (George W.); p. 127-136. (Box 6)
      Population.; Caribbean Area.
    - The Motherhood Tables of the 1946 Census of the West Indies, 1953; RISM 17420; Roberts, G. W. (George W.); p. 176-186. (Box 6)
    - Some Issues in the Study of Small Populations, 1976; RISM 17422; Roberts, G. W. (George W.); p. 37-46. (Box 6)
    - The Demographic Position of the Caribbean, 1963; RISM 20199; Roberts, G. W. (George W.); p. 81-124. (Box 6)
    - Populations of Caribbean and Other Countries Participating in the 1970 Census, 1971; RISM 20197; University of the West Indies (Mona, Jamaica). Department of Sociology. Census Research Programme; 1 page (Box 6)
    - Area and Population of the West Indies, 1961; RISM 23175; O'Loughlin, Carleen; 5 pages (Box 6)
    - Movements in Population and the Labour Force, 1960; RISM 24235; Roberts, G. W. (George W.); p. 24-47. (Box 6)
    - Some Demographic Considerations of West Indian Federation, 1957; RISM 24236; Roberts, G. W. (George W.); p. 262-285. (Box 6)
    - Census Research Programme for the West Indies, 1960-1970; RISM 25774; Roberts, G. W. (George W.); 12 pages (Box 6)
    - The Origins and Socio-Economic Charateristics of the Foreign Born Population in Dominica, St. Lucia and St. Vincent, 2002; RISM 26929; De Albuquerque, Klaus; 12 pages; 12.0 (Box 6)
  - Caribbean Area: Power Resources (Box 6)
    - Caribbean Development Bank: Electric Power, 1981; RISM 20350; Caribbean Development Bank; 13 pages (Box 6)
      Caribbean Area.; Power resources.
    - The Energy Crisis and the Caribbean, \1974; RISM 20352; Segal, Aaron; 2 pages (Box 6)
      Power resources.; Caribbean Area.
  - Caribbean Area: Printing (Box 7)
    - The Printing of the Honduras Almanack, 1977; RISM 20353; Cave, Roderick; 7 pages (Box 7)
      Caribbean Area.; Printing.
    - The First Printers in Jamaica, 1977; RISM 20354; Cave, Roderick; 23 pages (Box 7)
      Printing.; Caribbean Area.
    - The Plantocracy's Passion for 'Porcupine', 1977; RISM 20355; Cave, Roderick; 4 pages (Box 7)
    - Some Aspects of Early Printing and the Book Trade in the West Indies, 1977; RISM 20356; Cave, Roderick; 44 pages (Box 7)
    - Two Jamaican Printers: William Daniell & Curtis Brett, 1977; RISM 20357; Cave, Roderick; 17 pages (Box 7)
    - Two Early Advertisements from the S't. George's Chronicle', Grenada, 1977; RISM 20358; Cave, Roderick; 6 pages (Box 7)
    - The First 'Trinidad Guardian', 1977; RISM 20359; Cave, Roderick; 11 pages (Box 7)